Thomas Maestas

Multilingual Web App Developer, thomasmaestas.net , data analysis and visualization with Python, R, JavaScript

thomas76milton@gmail.com

Summary

My consulting services focus on latest technology with a Master's level data analysis methodology. My data analysis experience focused on education evaluation in K-12 and higher education. Now, I handle nearly all domains of data analysis. I focus on web-app design and development, specializing in data visualization with JavaScript and Python.I use Python, R, and Stata command-line research to gain perspective in statistical analysis. I also have five years' qualitative case-study research experience. I was born in Idaho, spent my early childhood in Paris, France, and later enjoyed residence in Buffalo, NY, Amarillo,TX, and Albuquerque, NM, where I now work and live.

Experience

Web App Development Consultant

January 2016 - Present

Thomas provides contractual services and consulting for big & small data and web solutions since 2016 T M M Data Tech Consulting

Doctoral Teaching Assistant

September 2016 - Present

Contractual Research Associate

January 2016 - April 2016 (4 months)

Web, Data and Evaluation Research Consulting Services for Evaluation Service

Project Assistant

August 2015 - December 2015 (5 months)

TRIO Student Support Services, (Minority- and Income-based Equity and Diversity); Qualitative Data Analyst;

Education

The University of New Mexico

Master of Arts (MA), Sociology, 2012 - 2015

Activities and Societies: Center for Academic Program Support (CAPS) Student Advisory Council Board member.

Université de Montréal

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Sociology, 2016 - 2020

University of New Mexico

Master of Arts (M.A.), Sociology, Criminology, 2012 - 2015

Activities and Societies: GPSA Representative for Sociology Graduate Student Association (SGSA). 2015-2016.

Thomas Maestas

Multilingual Web App Developer, thomasmaestas.net , data analysis and visualization with Python, R, JavaScript

thomas76milton@gmail.com



Contact Thomas on LinkedIn